hi Bret contas here uh this video is um
going to show off my unique hamstring
exercise that I do while some of them
are unique some of them are common but
uh of course I do you know Romanian
deadlifts single legegg rdls and good
mornings but those are axial exercises
the ones I'm going to show you today uh
are anroop posterior exercises front to
back they work your hamstring the mean
hamstring activation is a little bit
higher with these actually a lot higher
with these than with the axial exercises
so I'm just going to roll through a
bunch of different exercises I'm not
going to use a lot of weight I'm just
using this video to show the different
exercise so the first two are just uh
the reverse hyper and the single leg
reverse hyper
so that's the reverse hyper and then you
can do it one Leed at
[Music]
time okay these straight leg uh hip
Piper extension exercis or straight leg
Andro posterior exercis are the best
hamstring activation exercises the next
one is going to be the back extension
now this I call the back extension this
here is I call the 45° dier they have
different activation levels with the
back extension working more hamstring
and more glue so the more horizontal you
are the more anal posterior the vector
is the greater the activation so few
different ways to do this one you can do
it with a
dumbbell you can do it with a
band
or you can do it in the prisoner
position which is really
tough that's one leg at a
time okay now I'm moving on to uh the
straight leg bridge now this is for
people who don't have a reverse hyper or
a back extension you want to do the
straight leg
bridge
now one way to do
it is
[Applause]
this you just thrust up like
that now you can do this two legs at a
time oh also put a dumbbell right
there and then my favorite this
increases the range of
motion just hang from a
barbell just like
this so
from the floor double leg single leg and
then hanging or a suspended uh variation
all right next I'm going to show
you
um the Glide what I made this one up I
call it the gliding leg
curl and
uh
basically
it's kind of a combination of hip
extension and knee
flexion
so I'm going to
extend curl
forward
forward this one works really good
extend curl
forward
extend curl forward and that can be done
two legs at a time
also
try this one it's amazing all right
that's called the gliding leg curl and
the single leg gliding leg
curl
um now let's
see I'm going to show you the manual
glute ham
ra
[Music]
um and this
one
[Applause]
now then there's the kneeling hip
extension exercise this one's really
unique you
just bend
over
and you can hold on to a dumbbell too
like that when you do this exercise so
manual glue ham raise and then
kneeling hip
extension which is a very difficult
exercise if you do it right all right
moving
along uh now I going to show you the
glute ham
raise
now this one
here totally different activation than
the manual the manual is mostly all
hamstring this one works the glutes too
so
just come
up you want the knes to think down a
little bit if you want glute activation
now this one you can use a
dumbbell
too heavy I can move it
back this one's from Elite Fitness if I
get five holes showing that's the right
position for me and I can use the dumbb
here still a little too heavy that's 50
lb or again I can use the the band in
this method I just use one STR on that
come
on I'm not using full range but my
hamstrings are tired
okay sliding leg
curl and the dumbbell sliding leg curl
um this one will need to come
inside and you just need a
towel
we're just going to put our feet up the
slide board works better but we lay down
and uh I'm just going to thrust upwards
Mo my legs
in keep the hips
high you can do this one leg at a time
you can also put a dumbbell right here
in your lap when you do that exercise
and you you
can put weight onto the towel or hook a
band around your ankles and connect it
to a a pole or a rack that way it's more
resistance when you do the knee flexing
part anyway those are some of the unique
hamstring exercises I do um one day I'll
film a better video with this but I was
trying to rush and get it out cuz
someone on the my t- muscle Forum uh
asked for this
this video so anyway hope you liked it
thanks a lot